allblacks.com 2019-12-15

# Privacy Policy - NZR websites and Mobile Apps » allblacks.com

Team All Blacks is organised by New Zealand Rugby ('NZR', 'we' or 'us'). We take your privacy extremely seriously.

By registering for Team All Blacks, you consent, and authorise, us to collect, hold, use, and disclose your personal information in accordance with the terms set out in this Privacy Policy (as updated from time to time).

 ** _How we collect Information about you_**

We collect personal information about you:

  * Directly from you when: 
    * register for Team All Blacks or any NZR online services;
    * subscribe to emails from Team All Blacks or us;
    * make enquiries of Team All Blacks or us; or
    * when you communicate with us directly or through social media or other third party accounts that you have linked to your Team All Blacks registration or your log on to other NZR websites;
  * From other people or organisations when you authorise us to contact them to obtain personal information about you.
  * Through your use of our websites.

**_The kind of personal information we collect_**

We only collect the personal information you give to us or authorise us to collect from other people or sources.  The information we collect may include your name, address, email address, date of birth, gender, phone number and IP address (including country IP address originates from).

  * We may also collect information about: 
    * the teams you support;
    * your preferences for receiving email updates, marketing communications and other subscription information; and
    * any other personal information you may choose to provide to us, or authorise other persons to provide to us.

If you choose not to provide us with personal information, we’ll be unable to provide access to certain content or services.

 ** _How we use your personal information_**

We will primarily use your personal information:

  * to provide you services, offers and/or communications associated with Team All Blacks or that you have requested or for which you have subscribed, which may include: 
    * News, offers and promotions about the All Blacks and/or other national teams;
    * News, offers & promotions from selected competitions & teams;
    * Information about ticketing, hospitality and travel packages;
    * Offers or promotions from our commercial partners;
    * Great offers from the All Blacks official retail stores;
    * Training / Coaching information from NZR; and
    * For any other purpose that we notify you of at the time your personal information is collected.

We may communicate with you by email or, where you provide us with your mobile number, by text/picture/video message.  

We may use your personal information to create an individual profile for you so that we can enhance your user experience, including understanding and respecting your preferences and providing you with details of offers and opportunities that we think may be of interest to you, where you have agreed to receive them.  If you have not consented to us doing this, you can ask us not to use a profile of you for this purpose.

 **Withdrawing consent**

If we rely on your consent as our legal basis for processing your personal information, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time.

 **Restricting processing**

You can ask us to 'block' or suppress the processing of your personal information in certain circumstances, such as where you contest the accuracy of that personal information or you object to us doing so.  If you are entitled to restriction and if we've shared your personal information with others, we will let them know about the restriction where it is reasonably possible for us to do so.

 **Right to object**

You can ask us to stop processing your personal information, and we will do so, if we are

  * processing your personal information on the basis of the legitimate interests of us or a third party, unless we can demonstrate overriding compelling legitimate grounds for the processing, or the processing is required for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or
  * processing your personal information for direct marketing purposes.

**_How we may share your personal information_**

We may share your personal information with organisations that we may appoint to carry out administration, processing and other services on our behalf. These service providers will not be authorised by us to use or disclose your personal information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf, or to comply with legislation.

We may also disclose your personal information for the purposes of safety and security to relevant law enforcement bodies, or as may be authorised by you.

If you have linked your Team All Blacks registration, or your log on to other NZR websites, with a social media or other third party account you may hold, that social media organisation or third party may receive information about your visits to, and activities on, Team All Blacks and other NZR websites.

 **Cookies and Analytics**

Like many other website operators, we may use 'cookies' on NZR websites including Team All Blacks. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive and are used to record how you navigate the NZR website on each visit, including providing us with information about pages and advertisements (including click through from emails) which have been viewed, how frequently particular pages are visited and the most popular areas of NZR websites.

We may use cookies to enrich your experience of using NZR websites by allowing us to develop and improve NZR websites to reflect your interests by tailoring what you see to reflect what we have learned about your preferences during your visits to NZR websites. This will mean some of your stored browsing history can be accessed by us.

In addition to cookies, we may use Google Analytics and other tracking software including, but not limited to, Google, Facebook, Instagram and Twitter retargeting throughout NZR websites to understand and optimise user experience and to improve NZR advertising. This tracking software collects and analyses certain types of information, including cookies, IP addresses, device and software identifiers, referring and exit URLs, onsite behaviour and usage information, and other similar information.

We and any of our third party analytics service providers may:

  * use cookies to anonymously track and target advertising based on your browsing behaviour; and
  * use the cookies of that analytics service provider together with the cookies of another analytics provider to inform, optimise, and serve ads based on a user's past visits to this website.

NZR websites may also detect and use your IP address or domain name for internal web traffic monitoring and capacity purposes, or to otherwise administer the relevant NZR websites, but no personal information is collected.

Patterns of use by visitors to Team All Blacks website may be tracked for the purposes of providing improved service and content based on review of user’s website traffic patterns.

 **Turning off cookies and opting out of analytics**

You do not have to accept cookies and can change your browser settings to prevent cookies being stored on your computer. But, if you do turn cookies off this will limit the service that we are able to provide to you and may affect your visitor experience.

For further information on cookies and how to switch them off see [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

You can opt-out of Google Analytics using the Ads Settings ([www.google.com/settings/ads](http://www.google.com/settings/ads)).

 **Storage and Security**

We will only hold your personal information for as long as necessary for the purposes for which it was collected (unless otherwise required by law).

We will take reasonable steps to safely and securely store your personal information against loss, unauthorised access, disclosure, use, modification or other misuse. However, we cannot guarantee the security of information you provide to us via electronic means as information sent over the internet may be unsecure.

 **Overseas disclosures**

Your personal information may be held by us in New Zealand. It may also be held on our behalf by service providers who are located in either New Zealand or Australia.

 **Accessing and Correcting Your Personal Information**

You are entitled to request access to, and correction of, the personal information we hold about you.

If the information you have requested can be readily retrieved, and subject to any lawful grounds for withholding, we will provide you with a copy of the personal information you have requested.

You may update or correct your personal information online by logging into your Team All Blacks account. You can also contact us in writing or by email. If we agree with the

correction requested, we will make the change.  If we do not make the correction requested, you can ask for your request to be kept with the personal information of yours that we hold.

If you no longer want to remain a member of Team All Blacks, you are able to cancel your Team All Blacks membership (see the “Cancel membership” link under Account settings on the Team All Blacks website (www.teamallblacks.com).

 ** _Requesting Erasure of Your Personal Information_**

You can ask us to delete or remove your personal information in some circumstances, such as where we no longer need it, if you withdraw your consent (where applicable) or you validly object to the processing.  If you are entitled to erasure we will comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable.  Note, even after our reasonable efforts to erase, there may be some residual information that could remain within our databases and other records which is not removed. We may also need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes, for compliance with our legal obligations, for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims and/or to complete any transactions started before your request is received.  If we have shared your personal information with others, we will let them know about your request where reasonably possible.

 **Data portability**

You have the right, in certain circumstances, to obtain personal information you've provided us with (in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format) and to reuse it elsewhere. You may also ask us to transfer this data to a third party of your choice where this is technically practicable.

 **Right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority**

If you are based in the European Economic Area (EAA) and have a concern about any aspect of our privacy practices, including the way we've handled your personal information, you can report it to the relevant Supervisory Authority in the EEA.

If you ask us, where it is reasonably possible and lawful for us to do so, we will tell you who we have shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly.

Please be aware that some of these rights may be limited or unavailable, for example where we have an overriding interest or legal obligation to continue to process the data.

 **Privacy Policy Review and Update**

We may, from time to time, amend or update this Privacy Policy. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be available on www.teamallblacks.com.

 **Contact Us**

You can contact us at any time regarding your personal information through our Privacy Officer who can be contacted by the following means:

 **Address** :New Zealand Rugby,PO Box 2172, Wellington 6140, New Zealand

 **Email** : [[email protected]](https://mail.google.com/mail/?view=cm&fs=1&tf=1&to=privacyofficer@nzrugby.co.nz)

 **Phone** : +64 (0)4 499 4995

 ** _Team All Blacks Privacy Policy last updated July 2018_**
